Visual Geometry Group (VGG)
Department of Engineering Science
University of Oxford

⊠ cxzheng@robots.ox.ac.uk

☐ https://chuanxiaz.com/

☐ lyndonzheng

Chuanxia Zheng

Research Interests

His research interests focus on computer vision and machine learning, especially for generative models. He has done a wide range of work on 2D and 3D scene synthesis, with the goal of *synthesizing a photorealistic virtual world* via generative AI. In particular, on topics:

- 3D reconstruction and generation from limited views or videos.
- o 3D editing (e.g., decomposition, recomposition, and completion) via object-centric perception.
- Generative models for physical world understanding.

Research interests: secne understanding and segmentation

• Multi-modalities (1D, 2D, 3D, and 4D) generation and understanding.

Education

Nanyang Technological University Ph.D. in Computer Science, SCSE Thesis: Synthesizing Photorealistic Images with Deep Generative Learning	2017.08-2021.07
Advisors: Tat-Jen Cham and Jianfei Cai Beihang University MA.E. in Automation Science Thesis: Context-based Indoor Scene Understanding for Mobile Robot	2014.09-2017.03
Advisors: Jianhua Wang and Weihai Chen Beijing Jiaotong University	2010.09-2014.07
B.E. in Electronic and Information Engineering Highest Honours (Outstanding Graduate of Beijing), Advisor: Ze Liu	2010.00 2011.01
Employment	
University of Oxford PostDoctoral Researcher Fellow in Computer Vision Research interests: 2D and 3D scene synthesis using unsupervised learning	2022.12-now
Tap Mobile AI research counselor in computer vision and machine learning group Research interests: 2D image generation, completion and translation	2022.09-2022.11
Monash University Postdoctoral Research Fellow at Monash Research Institute of Science and Technology Research interests: 2D image generation and 3D generation	2021.08-2022.08
Huawei Research Research assistant at Noah's Ark Lab Research interests: face recognition and generation	2017.01-2017.06
Research Experience	
VinAI, The national AI research Lab of Vietnam, Vietnam, Dr. Hung Bui Cooperator on high quality image generation and data compression three papers accepted by NeurIPS(1), ICLR(1), ICML(1)	2021.11-2022.08
Department of Data Science & AI, Monash University, Australia, Prof. Jianfei cai Research interests: nature scene generation and completion three papers accepted by CVPR(1), ECCV(2), one paper submitted to TPAMI	2021.08-2022.08
Institute for Media Innovation (IMI), NTU, Singapore, Prof. Nadia Thalmann Research interests: photorealistic image generation seven papers accepted by CVPR(2), ECCV(1), ICCV(1), SIGGRAPH(1) and IJCV(2)	2017.08-2021.06
IR&MCT Lab, Beihang University, China, Prof. Weihai Chen	2014.09 – 2017.03

Awards & Honors

CVPR 2023 Outstanding Reviewers (232/7000+)	2023
NeurIPS 2022 Scholar/Travel Award	2022
NTU Presidential Postdoctoral Fellowship	2022
NTU Outstanding PhD Thesis Award	2022
TMM Outstanding Reviewer Award	2021
NTU Research Scholarship	2017
Outstanding Graduate of Beijing	2014
National Second Prize of the National Electronic Design Contest of China (Best one in Beijing	g) 2013
Hanergy Scholarship Award (Top 1%)	2012
Siemens Scholarship Award (Top 1%)	2011
Press Coverage	
Sber.ru: MoVQ — 0.1 means a lot for text-image generation Kandinsky 2.1 (Github: 2.3 K)	2023
Phys.org: Researchers unravel cell biology through artificial intelligence	
NTU News: NTU SCSE Outstanding PhD Thesis Award 2022	2022
Zhuanzhi: How to create photorealistic images? Ph.D. Thesis by Dr. Zheng	2022
kknews, Sohu, NetEase: AgileGAN — a tool for creating stylized portraits (Demo: 10K in 7 day	rs) 2021
Academic Services	
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ	
Journal Reviewer. TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer.	
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ	
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS	2023.06
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer. CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks	
Journal Reviewer. TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer. CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT	2023.06
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU	2023.06
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford	2023.06 2023.04 2023.04
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU, Link	2023.06 2023.04 2023.04 2022.09
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer. CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU, Link Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford	2023.06 2023.04 2023.04 2022.09 2022.08
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer. CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU, Link Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH	2023.06 2023.04 2023.04 2022.09 2022.08 2022.06
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU, Link Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, USTC	2023.06 2023.04 2023.04 2022.09 2022.08 2022.06 2022.01
Journal Reviewer. TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer. CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU, Link Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, USTC Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2023.06 2023.04 2023.04 2022.09 2022.08 2022.06 2022.01 2019.11
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU, Link Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, USTC Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2023.06 2023.04 2023.04 2022.09 2022.08 2022.06 2022.01 2019.11
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU, Link Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, USTC Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU	2023.06 2023.04 2023.04 2022.09 2022.08 2022.01 2019.11 2018.06
Journal Reviewer. TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer. CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU, Link Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, USTC Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU Teaching Teaching Assistant, B16: Software Engineering, Undergraduate, Oxford	2023.06 2023.04 2023.04 2022.09 2022.06 2022.01 2019.11 2018.06
Journal Reviewer TPAMI, IJCV, TIP, TMM(Outstanding Reviewer Award, 2021), TCSVT, TVCJ Conference Reviewer CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, ICLR, NeurIPS, ICML, SIGGRAPH, ICRA, IROS Talks Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, HIT Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, SCSE, NTU Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, SCSE Gratuate Chat Series Discussion, NTU, Link Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Visual Geometry Group, Oxford Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Computer Vision & Geometry Group, ETH Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Graphics & Geometric Computing Laboratory, USTC Pluralistic Image Completion, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Institute of Media Innovation, NTU Teaching Teaching Assistant, B16: Software Engineering, Undergraduate, Oxford Teaching, Generative AI, Graduate, Oxford	2023.06 2023.04 2023.04 2022.09 2022.06 2022.01 2019.11 2018.06

Advising

PhD students	
Zeyu Wang, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2023-presen
Fengming Liu, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2023-presen
Tianhao Wu, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2023-presen
Minghui Hu, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham	2022-presen
Yuedong Chen, Monash University, co-supervised with Prof. Jianfei Cai	2021-present
Master students	
Jingbo Zhao, University of Oxford, Undergraduate Part B extend Essay	2023-presen

Publications CVPR(3), ECCV(3), ICCV(2), NeurIPS(2), ICLR(1), ICML(1), IJCV(2), SIGGRAPH(1)

- [21] Minghui Hu, Jianbin Zheng, Daqing Liu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Tat-Jen Cham. Cocktail: Mixing multi-modality control for text-conditional image generation. In *Thirty-seventh Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)*, 2023.
- [20] Chuanxia Zheng and Andrea Vedaldi. Online clustered codebook. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision(ICCV)*, 2023.
- [19] Long Tung Vuong, Trung Le, He Zhao, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Mehrtash Harandi, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Vector quantized wasserstein auto-encoder. In *The Fortieth International Conference on Machine Learning* (*ICML*), 2023.
- [18] Minghui Hu, Chuanxia Zheng, Heliang Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Zuopeng Yang, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Ponnuthurai N. Suganthan. Unified discrete diffusion for simultaneous vision-language generation. In The Eleventh International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023.
- [17] Chuanxia Zheng, Long Tung Vuong, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Movq: Modulating quantized vectors for high-fidelity image generation. In *Thirty-sixth Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems* (NeurIPS), 2022.
- [16] Jyothsna Vasudevan*, **Chuanxia Zheng***, James G. Wan, Tat-Jen Cham, Lim Chwee Teck, and Javier G. Fernandez. From qualitative data to correlation using deep generative networks: Demonstrating the relation of nuclear position with the arrangement of actin filaments. *PloS one*, 17(7):e0271056, 2022.
- [15] Qianyi Wu, Xian Liu, Yuedong Chen, Kejie Li, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianfei Cai, and Jianming Zheng. Object-compositional neural implicit surfaces. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision* (*ECCV*), 2022.
- [14] Yuedong Chen, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Sem2nerf: Converting single-view semantic masks to neural radiance fields. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2022.
- [13] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Bridging global context interactions for high-fidelity image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR)*, pages 11512–11522, June 2022.
- [12] Chuanxia Zheng, Duy-Son Dao, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Visiting the invisible: Layer-by-layer completed scene decomposition. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(12):3195–3215, 2021.
- [11] Yujun Cai, Yiwei Wang, Yiheng Zhu, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Junsong Yuan, Jun Liu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Sijie Yan, Henghui Ding, Xiaohui Shen, Ding Liu, and Nadia Magnenat Thalmann. A unified 3d human motion synthesis model via conditional variational auto-encoder. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision*(*ICCV*), pages 11645–11655, 2021.
- [10] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic free-form image completion. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(10):2786–2805, 2021.

- [9] Guoxian Song, Linjie Luo, Jing Liu, Wan-Chun Ma, Chunpong Lai, Chuanxia Zheng, and Tat-Jen Cham. Agilegan: stylizing portraits by inversion-consistent transfer learning. ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG), 40(4):1–13, 2021.
- [8] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. The spatially-correlative loss for various image translation tasks. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR), pages 16407–16417, 2021.
- [7] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, pages 1438–1447, 2019.
- [6] Tianyi Zhang, Jingyi Yang, Chuanxia Zheng, Guosheng Lin, Jianfei Cai, and Alex C Kot. Task-in-all domain adaptation for semantic segmentation. In 2019 IEEE Visual Communications and Image Processing (VCIP), pages 1–4. IEEE, 2019.
- [5] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. T2net: Synthetic-to-realistic translation for solving single-image depth estimation tasks. In Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), pages 767–783, 2018.
- [4] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Multi-class indoor semantic segmentation with deep structured model. *The Visual Computer* (*TVCJ*), 34(5):735–747, 2018.
- [3] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning aggregated features and optimizing model for semantic labeling. *The Visual Computer* (*TVCJ*), 33(12):1587–1600, 2017.
- [2] Chuanxia Zheng, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Semantic segmentation based on aggregated features and contextual information. In 2016 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics (ROBIO), pages 862–867. IEEE, 2016.
- Jianhua Wang, Chuanxia Zheng, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning contextual information for indoor semantic segmentation. In 2016 IEEE 11th Conference on Industrial Electronics and Applications (ICIEA), pages 1639–1644. IEEE, 2016.

Preprints

- [6] Tianhao Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Ipo-ldm: Depth-aided 360-degree indoor rgb panorama outpainting via latent diffusion model. *Under reviewer on ICLR*.
- [5] Long Tung Vuong, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Manh Luong, Thanh-Toan Do, Dinh Phung, and Trung Le. Kefi: Kernel-based feature identification for generalizable classification. *Under reviewer on ICLR*.
- [4] Guanqi Zhan, Chuanxia Zheng, Weidi Xie, and Andrew Zisserman. Amodal completion in the wild. Under reviewer on 3DV.
- [3] Yuedong Chen, Haofei Xu, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Explicit correspondence matching for generalizable neural radiance fields. *Under reviewer on 3DV*.
- [2] Yuzhu Ji, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. One-shot human motion transfer via occlusion-robust flow prediction and neural texturing. *Under reviewer on TNNLS*.
- [1] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Linjie Luo, and Dinh Phung. High-quality pluralistic image completion via code sharing. *Under reviewer on TPAMI*.